[Music]
let a
b
and c
all be sets
and suppose that f is a function from a
to b
and g is a function from b to c
then the function g composed f
is the function from a to c
defined by the rule that g composed f of
a is equal to g of f a
that is we send a into f
and send the resulting output from b
into g
the composition takes a directly to that
output so that g composed f of a is
equal to g of f of a
let's see this definition in action as
we prove that function composition is
associative
this means that if we have three
functions f g and h
then the composition of h with g
composed f is equal to h composed g
composed with f
in particular no matter what element
from the domain a we plug into these
functions the outputs will be equal
let's see this proof visually let a b
c
and d all be sets
and suppose that f is a function from a
to b g is a function from b to c and h
is a function from c to d
then we know that g composed f is a
function from a to c and h compose g is
a function from b to d
start with an arbitrary element x from
the domain a
we can send x through f
send the output through g
and send that output through h resulting
in the element h of g of f of x
now we end at the exact same element
when we send x through g composed f
and then the resulting output through h
so h composed with a g composed f of x
is equal to h of g composed f of x which
is equal to h of g of f of x
similarly we ended that exact same
element when we send x through f and the
resulting output through h composed g
so h composed g composed with f x is
equal to h composed g of f of x which is
equal to h of g of f x
therefore the two compositions map x to
the same element no matter what x is
so the two compositions are equal as
functions
[Music]
you